momentive.com 2019-04-14

# Momentive.com™ Official Site | Privacy Policy

**Momentive Website Privacy Policy**

Revised October, 2017

**IDENTIFICATION OF THE DATA CONTROLLER**

This website is controlled and operated by Momentive Performance Materials Inc., a Delaware (USA) corporation with its headquarters/principal office at 260 Hudson River Road, Waterford, NY 12188 , USA, and its subsidiaries (“Momentive” or “We”).

**SCOPE**

This Privacy Policy describes the information collection, use, and disclosure practices of the Momentive website hosted at www.momentive.com (the “Site”). 

From time to time, Momentive may make changes to this Privacy Policy.  Such changes do not have retroactive effect and will only apply to our future practices.  Any such future modifications to this Privacy Policy will be posted on the Site, with an updated “Revised” date at the top.  Continue to use the Site after each revision date only if you agree to the most recent changes. 

**INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE**

**Personal Information**

Whenever you browse the Site, Momentive’s web server will temporarily log each access to its log file. Through this process, Momentive will collect and store the below data until they are deleted in accordance with statutory requirements: 

  * IP address of requesting system
  * Time and date of access
  * Name and URL of the data accessed on our web server
  * Transferred data volume
  * Confirmation whether download was successful
  * Header information identifying the requesting browser and operating system

Momentive processes this data only to the extent required for the purposes of providing access to the content of the Site and to secure and administer Momentive’s system. The IP address will only be analyzed in case of security incidents on Momentive’s systems.

You may browse most areas of the Site without providing any further personal information to Momentive. To access some services or areas on the Site, you may be asked to register and to provide information about you and/or your company such as name, job title, email address, and other information.  This information will enable Momentive to provide services and/or information to you. If you order products or use certain services available through this Site, you may be asked to provide further information, including, but not limited to, billing information (such as credit card account information), product information, and other personal information. Momentive may also collect other information from you when you provide comments or participate in surveys. The type of information collected is always transparent to you in advance, as the relevant registration process or survey will ask for such information explicitly. We use such personal information to provide our services and otherwise operate our business, consistent with this Privacy Policy and any notice that may be provided at the time of collection. In most cases, personal information is used only to respond to your inquiry or to process your request. If we would like to use your personal information for marketing purposes, we will first ask for your consent. 

If you chose to use the online job search program, you will be asked to provide additional information about yourself that is required as part of the application process, such as your address and other contact information, your educational history, or your work history.  The members of our Human Resources staff will review and process your application, and the information you provide may become part of your personnel file if you accept a job at Momentive. Even if you do not accept a job, the information you provide may also be kept on file for purposes of identifying future employment opportunities for you at Momentive, subject to your prior consent. 

**Cookies**

To ensure a good user experience, our Site uses system cookies that contain a unique number, your 'session ID', which allows our server to recognize your computer and 'remember' what you've done on the Site. The benefits of these are: 

  * You only need to log in once if you're navigating secure areas of the Site
  * You are able to use interactive elements of the Site, such as forms
  * Our server can distinguish between your computer and other users, so you can see the information that you have requested.

When you close your browser the cookie will be deleted and the Site will 'forget' your session pursuant to the table below.

The following table gives details of the different types of cookies that might be used during a session.

**Cookie Names** |  **Stays Until** |  **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
  
**System-Cookies:**

**Ecm**

**ASP.NET_SessionId**

**EktGUID**

**Hubspotutk**

**DismissCookie**

**_lo_rid**

**__hstc**

**__hssc**

**BC_BANDWIDTH**

**__hssrc**

**_lo_u**

**mpm_site_visit**

**_lo_v**

**ASPXAUTH**

**__lotr**

**lo_form_submits_XX**

**CurrentUserLanguage**

**ExplicitLanguage**

| 

Deletes when session is closed

Deletes when session is closed

1 Year

Does not expire

1 Day

1 Hour

2 Years

1 Hour

Deleted when session is closed

Deletes when session is closed

2 Years

1 Hour

1 Year

Deletes when session is closed

1 Hour

Deletes when session is closed

1 Year

1 Day

|  We use various system cookies to help with the operation of our website and your user experience.  These include cookies to help maintain bandwidth metrics so we can optimize your experience and display the products you have viewed to help provide you with the most relevant information.   
  
If you would like to opt out of the advantages of these cookies, you can read in the ‘help’ function on your browser how to adjust your browser to prevent these cookies, accept new cookies, or delete existing cookies. The “help” function also explains how to block all cookies or set up notifications for new cookies. However, rejection of a cookie may limit the functionality that is available to you when you visit this Site. 

**Google Analytics**

This Site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses the below cookies, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the Site analyze how users use it. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. 

**Cookie Name  ** | **Purpose  ** | **Stays Until  **  
---|---|---  
**

Google Analytics Cookies: 

  __utma, __utmb, __utmc, __utmt, __utmz, _ga, _gat ** |  We use Google Analytics for our web analytics tool.  The information collected helps us to continually address the needs of our visitors.  Our configuration uses the Anonoymize IP function provided by Google to protect the identity of each user.  Further information as well as Opt-Out capabilities can be found at <http://www.google.com/analytics>.     
| Google Analytics Cookies may exist up to 2 years.   
**Cookie Name  ** | **Purpose  ** | **Stays Until  **  
---|---|---  
**

Google Analytics Demographic Cookies: 

  __nid, __sid, __dsid, __flc, __aid, __taid, __exchange_uid  ** |  We use Google Analytics Demographic feature for our   web analytics tool.  The information   collected helps us to continually address the needs of our visitors.  Our configuration uses the Anonoymize IP   function provided by Google to protect the identity of each user.  Further information as well as Opt-Out   capabilities can be found at <http://www.google.com/analytics>.     
| 

Google Analytics Demographic Cookies may   exist up to 2 years.

IP-anonymisation is active on this Site, your IP address will be truncated within your domestic region before transfer to a Google server. Only in exceptional cases will the whole IP address be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. 

Google will use this information on our behalf for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Site, compiling reports on website activity for us and providing to us other services relating to website activity and internet usage. The IP-address that your browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Site. 

You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Addon for your current web browser, by clicking the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. 

**Social Plugins**

Our Site uses social plugins (“Plugins”) provided by the social networks Facebook, Google +1 and LinkedIn as well as by the microblogging platform Twitter. The respective services are operated by Facebook Inc., Google Inc., LinkedIn Corporation and Twitter Inc. (each an “Operator”). 

  * The Operator of Facebook (facebook.com) is Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. Its Plugins are identifiable by a Facebook logo (white letter f on blue background or a thumb up icon) or the notice “Facebook Social Plugin”. For a full list of all Plugins, please see <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>. 
  * The Operator of LinkedIn (linkedin.com) is LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Its Plugins are identified by the LinkedIn or SlideShare logos of the “Share”-Button, as can be reviewed at [http://linkedin.com](http://linkedin.com/). 
  * The Operator of Twitter (twitter.com) is Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Its Plugins are identified by the Twitter logos and an overview is available at <https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-for-websites/overview.html>. 

When you visit a page of our Site that contains a Plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection to the servers of the respective Operator. The Operator directly transfers the Plugin content to your browser which embeds the latter into the Site, enabling the Operator to receive information about your access to the respective page of our Site. This applies even if you do not have a login or are not logged in at the network of the Operator. Your browser will transfer the information (including your IP address) to the servers of the respective Operator directly, where it will be stored and used by the Operator. The servers may be based outside your domestic region. 

We have no influence on the data gathered by the Plugins. For the information on the purpose and scope of data collection and procession by the respective Operators, as well as your rights in this respect and settings options for protecting your privacy, please visit the Operators’ privacy policies at: 

  * Facebook's privacy policy:                 <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>
  * Google's privacy policy:                      <https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy>
  * LinkedIn's privacy policy:                    <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>
  * Twitter’s privacy policy:                       <https://twitter.com/privacy>

If you are a member of one of the above networks and do not want the Operator to connect the data concerning your visit to our Site with your member data already stored by that Operator, please log out of the social network before entering our Site. In their privacy policies, the respective Operators may describe further options to block their Plugins. Also, at your option, you can use independent browser addons (e.g. „NoScript“ available at [https://noscript.net](https://noscript.net/)) to keep all or some Plugins from loading. 

**SHARING OF INFORMATION**

When you provide information to Momentive, it may be shared with third party service providers within and outside your domestic region to perform processing tasks or business functions for us or on our behalf. This includes fulfilling your requests, managing our customer relations and offering you Momentive products and services. Momentive does not share, sell, or lease personal information about you to any third parties for direct marketing use without your prior consent. 

Momentive may disclose information about you to third parties if we believe that we have a legal obligation to do so or where we believe disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.  In the event Momentive merges with another company, or another company acquires all or part of Momentive’s assets, including without limitation, in the event of bankruptcy, personal information compiled or owned by Momentive may be among the items transferred in that transaction. In addition, the information you provide may be shared with Momentive operating units or departments, as well as affiliates or other companies under ownership of Momentive Performance Materials Inc., whether located in the United States or in other parts of the world. 

**DATA SECURITY**

Momentive maintains adequate physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect your personal information from unauthorized access. Access to information about you is restricted to those Momentive workers who need to know the information to respond to your inquiry or request. 

**LINKS**

This Site may feature links to other websites. Momentive is not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by other sites. You should contact these companies directly if you have any questions about their collection or use of information about you.

**ACCESS TO YOUR DATA**

If you have a customer account at one of the Sites, Momentive gives you access to a broad range of information through your account that you may view and correct. Besides this, you have the right to receive confirmation from Momentive whether or not personal data about you is processed and where this is the case, to access to the personal data. In this respect, you may receive a copy of your personal data Momentive processes. For any further copies, Momentive reserves the right to charge a reasonable fee based on administrative costs. To exercise this right, please contact Momentive as set out below 

**CONTACT US**

Please contact Momentive if you wish to modify or verify personal information that you have submitted or if you have questions about the information that is maintained.

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [**_webprivacy@momentive.com_**](mailto:webprivacy@momentive.com).
